<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monica Bolles</title>
    <description>This is an expression of me.  Here you may find my art, my life, my love.   Most importantly the conversations of an artist in the world of science.   
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 22:36:01 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 22:36:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Net Art and Curation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the advent of the internet it was to be certain that artists would find ways to interact, build, and create ‘’art” for such a landscape.  As with any development of an idea that would form a paradigm shift into our next level of evolution, there were those that recognized the potential of the net for being a space where current constructs could be deconstructed and the future could be built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The net offers users a unique perspective on interaction.  Users are encouraged to click, play, and examine each page.  They may never have the time or patience to explore every single aspect a website has to offer, yet there is an ever present engagement with the ‘surf-the-web’ experience.  This idea of ‘click-holes’ has become a household term.  Everyone is familiar with the time they have spent down the rabbit’s hole of clicking on links.  Net art has often fully explored this concept.  Hypertext novels and electronic literature riddle pages with links to other pages, with links to even more pages, by the time you look up you’re not even sure where you started or where you have gone.  The journey fails temporal linearity as it capitalizes and perpetuates the attention disordered culture that we live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in this world artists have been given an opportunity to engage with their viewers/(users(?)) in a different way than traditional art galleries may afford.  As a child I remember the stiff atmosphere of an art gallery.  The cold white walls would decorate the paintings that stood still and iconic. Velvet ropes defined the borders between appreciation and criticism.  Guards were the warriors of silence and artistic preservation.  Words were meant to be whispered and hands were meant to stay by one’s side.  Maybe it was just me, but I always wanted to tear through all the borders and constrictions to feel the texture of the paint against my fingers.  I was sure that the artist’s secrets were held in between the strokes of paint that defined its mastery.  But in this environment the art seemed meant for only those that had the privledged knowledge that gave them the right to critically disseminate and dismantle the stagnant imagery hung on the wall by uttering pompeous remarks about what they could only theorize was an artistic meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net art on the other hand is for anyone and everyone, but mostly for those who take the time to engage.  Human exploration is key to understanding this art form. There is no velvet rope, there are no guards, this art can be experienced in the privacy of your own home, or when surrounded by people at a coffee shop or library.  You can share, you can never tell a sole, there are many choices to how you experience net art and all of it comes down to the way in which you choose to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curation of net art can be just as interactive and engaging.  The art gallery of the net can be whatever you define.  One of my personal favorites is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.easylife.org/desktop/&quot;&gt;Desktop It&lt;/a&gt;.  The gallery itself is an artistic statement to your desktop.  Within it are links to over fifty different pictures of desktops as well as some net art pieces.  However, this site also brings to light the inherent nature of curation in digital space, site deletion or movement.  Many of the links on this page are broken and thus is the case with many sites of curation.  It’s as if the artist walked into the art gallery and pulled their painting off the wall leaving a gaping hole to be observed by the masses.  Or maybe their piece was stolen, maybe there was a fire, maybe this art now exists nowhere and all we are left with is a blinking white page with a responding error message that makes us wonder if there was anything here to begin with at all.  The impermanence of net art is inherent within the medium.  While there is something so tangible to the way we interact and engage with it, there is also nothing physically viable that will define its existence for any guaranteed amount of time.  This art exists outside of space and will only exist for as long as the artist chooses to water and feed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I am a fan of the breaking down of borders, constitutions, and definitions.  The evolution of art within the net/web space has been at the forefront of challenging concepts of art and government for a while.  It asks questions about community, viewer engagement, scientific understanding, and even strives to redefine our current definitions of art and curatorial space.  My own interests lie heavily within examining the lines that blur art and science. The artist is now a scientific monger exploring at great depths the science and nature of their artistic expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EleVr is a research group that creates a series of art projects to explore and research their topics of interest.  In the project “&lt;a href=&quot;http://elevr.com/portfolio/monkey-see-monkey-do/&quot;&gt;Monkey See, Monkey Do&lt;/a&gt;” they built a 360-degree virtual reality environment in which the viewer can manipulate the number of monkeys they see in four dimensional space.  In their video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=286&amp;amp;v=ubfOeOtCNo4&quot;&gt;4Dmonkey.gif&lt;/a&gt; the evolution of art within these programmatic spaces is explored, and the lines that justify the separation of science and art become blurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thejohnnycashproject.com/&quot;&gt;The Johnny Cash Project&lt;/a&gt; is a massive web collaboration project to remix and recreate a “living portrait” of Johnny Cash. The website allows anyone to download and paint over a frame of Johnny Cash’s music video for “Ain’t No Grave”.  Anyone can then vote on their favorite frames and the ones that gain the most popularity are put into a music video that you can watch.  The frames that are included are changing all the time due to new frames being built and voted into existence.  The website offers up the potential for collaboration from people around the world and is a piece of art within itself.  It begs to question if art these days is ever a finalized piece of work or more of a platform to encourage new ways of human engagement and interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net art has grown and evolved since it’s early days.  Technology has advanced to a level where many things originally thought to be impossible are readily accessible.  We are entering into a new phase where web browsers can process 3D modeling, interactive audio, virtual reality, and large scale interactive projects.  This opens up a new world of creativity to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- *References:* 

[http://www.easylife.org/desktop/][desktop]

[http://elevr.com/portfolio/monkey-see-monkey-do/][monkey]

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=286&amp;v=ubfOeOtCNo4][4Dmonkey]

[http://www.thejohnnycashproject.com/][cash] --&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 12:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/18/Net_Art_and_Curation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/18/Net_Art_and_Curation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Objective and Method</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Objective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To contemplate the theory of resonance through the integration of physics, psychology, art, and music in an interactive multimedia performance piece accompanied by an interactive hypertext novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Method:  Hypertext&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the written presentation of my work I will create a hypertext that explores my thought process as well as the meetings and interactions that define the core moments of my research.  The hypertext will host written reflections on interviews, readings, and experiments as well as audio, video clips, and illustrations.  This method is meant to explore the relationships and connections that form between thoughts, conversations, and experiences during the research and creation process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/15/DSObjective_and_Method.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/15/DSObjective_and_Method.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>School</title>
        <description>&lt;body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in elementary school I attended Montessori school.  The classroom was an open room with mostly floor space.  There were no chairs and we would usually sit on the floor.  I can still picture the layout of the space.  There was a corner across from the door that allowed us entrance into the classroom.  In this corner there were stacks of books.  In the book corner existed a list that had many recommended readings on it.  I made it a point to check off as many of these readings from this list as I could.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;If you turned to your right, when in the book corner, there was one larger table with chairs.  We mostly used this space to make art or any project that you were working on that required a table.  Every year we would create a group art project and present it at the Boulder Art Museum.  We would go on a field trip to see it.  One year we created a quilt inspired by the artist Faith Ringgold.  We came up with the concept as a group and then each of us created a square that was later sewn into one larger whole.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;Most of the space; however, was just an open floor.  Here we would sit in a circle and play music, write, study, and learn.  Every morning we would start the day out by journaling in a notebook.  I still have the stacks of black and white etched composition books that we would write in.  It was here I learned about poetry and wrote many of my first poems.  It was also here I learned about astronomy and became fascinated with the stars and the history of all the men and women who had travelled to the moon.  Each subject flowed into the next.  There were no lines or distinctions.  The space was safe, bright, and inviting.  It was in this space I began developing many of my strongest skillsets.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;When I finally began attending public school I found it challenging to sit in the classroom the way they expected us to sit.  The desks were uncomfortable and I found it difficult to listen to the teacher as they droned on about who knows what. I would get in trouble for doodling on my notebook, or doing my homework in class, but I still managed to get straight A’s.  Mostly I was just bored.  It was easy to just remember information and regurgitate it, and writing seemed pretty natural to me at that point.  I don’t have many clear memories about my classes and what I learned during this time. What I do remember were my friends and the social connections I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I reached college I rediscovered my passion for learning.  My classes were harder, I could choose what subjects I wanted to study, and I had a big beautiful open campus to explore.  I still struggled to sit in a desk ‘properly’, but for the most part I was excited and stimulated about the knowledge that was to be gained.  Pretty quickly I learned that the university didn’t have a program that integrated all of the subjects that I was interested in so I devised my own program combining physics, psychology, art, and music.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;I was amazed at how many people would ask me how these subjects connected.  To me it was obvious.  Physics was the study of optics and acoustics, psychology was sensation and perception, and art was the application of these studies.  I think it is the drive to make these connections and the realization that they are not immediately apparent to everyone that makes me have the desire to create the art I wish to create.&lt;/p&gt;  


&lt;/body&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/14/DSSchool.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/14/DSSchool.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Key Points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;o	Integration – of physics, psychology, art, and music (core foundations of my undergraduate studies)
o	Integration – of self, the artist, and the scientist. 
o	Recognition of connection – between human and human, human and technology, human and 
knowledge.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/13/DSKeypoints.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/13/DSKeypoints.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resonance</title>
        <description>&lt;body&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		It’s the way you move across the room.  The way you breathe.  There is a solemn quiet that exudes beyond us and into time and space.  The timeline of our existence breaks down.  Disintegrates.  You and I are left to look at each other.  Maybe I should gain comfort in your smile.  And I do.  But there is something more beautiful in knowing that whatever we are is outside of time.  We have passed beyond the furthest dimension we could imagine.  So now we stand here, looking at each other.  I’ve never recognized your face the way I do in this light.  It glows with a solemn uncertainty that keeps me focused on every emotion that I exude.  Like perspiration seeping out my pours, I seep feeling.  Pure unadulterated feeling.  And you.  Who are you to do this to me?  But I can’t resist.  So I take your hand and we dance.  I feel your fingers grab me with a soft intent and suddenly I am connected, the subtleties of your motion direct me from one position to the next.  Never have I felt more alive.  Here in this moment we infringe upon our morality of conception.  We are all connected, so why do we fail to acknowledge those connections?  

	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 16:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/12/Resonance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/12/Resonance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Storytelling in the Digital Age</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the digital space time becomes an object to be manipulated and controlled.  The linearity of storytelling is no longer a necessity.  As we move through our ‘reality’, whatever that may be, there is a clear past, present, and future that moves linearly.  Time has an order and the stories that we tell tend to reflect that order; however, as technology advances and new ways of exploring story telling devices emerge we begin to recognize that time is not always so direct.  When we recall events through exploring the landscape of our memories the lines that define that linear understanding of time start to blur, and what are we left with but a blanket of a past sensation and feeling with no precise timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Shelley Jackson’s piece My Body the evolution of the story seems reminiscent of walking through your own memory.  Memories don’t happen linearly.  You don’t think about your past recalling all moments in the order in which they happened.  Memories pop up at random times, in varied order, and sometimes you skip to another memory before you’ve fully reminisced in the memory you were currently remembering.  There is no concept of linearity when recalling your past other than a vague sense of the order in which certain events occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Body seems to speak to the natural nature in which a mind processes and perceives the world around us.  As you move through the links you find yourself randomly jumping between thoughts and memories, just as you might if you were naturally thinking about your life and past events.  There is an authenticity that seemingly lacks in the more ‘traditional’ methods of linear stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Adrienne Eisen’s piece Six Sex Scenes there is that same feeling of being inside someone’s mind as they are thinking about and processing moments of their life.  Adrienne moves around different scenes that are more specific to memories or present occurrences.  In My Body there is deeper discussion of plain thought and reflections on life.  Still these two pieces strongly resemble the feeling of floating through your own mind. The story telling methods feel personal and intimate like you are glancing at the inner workings of someone’s thoughts.  You feel connected in a way that is unusual in other storytelling methods. You have been transported into the mind and feelings of the author or whatever character they are trying to present and you feel like you are getting to know all the secrets that they hold dear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology has advanced so have the methods for capturing time, predicting future, and dissolving the present.  In our current digital-world we find that we can move beyond the linear nature we are so used to in our physical reality.  A story no longer has to have a beginning, middle, and end.  A story can be experienced as a collection of memories, moments, and pieces of history that can be influenced by your very interaction with that story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both Bob Arrelano’s Sunshine 69 and Donna Leischman’s redridinghood the stories become completely different depending on the interaction of the viewer.  There are different paths to choose and different stories to be told.  Again we are transported out of time to a place where multiple realities can and do exist.  The questions of what if are asked and the directions of choosing different paths are revealed.&lt;br /&gt;
Again there is an authenticity to this method of storytelling as the story of one’s own life only unfolds due to the interactions and decisions that we make.  By offering the viewer an opportunity to influence the path the story takes, the author, creator, or whatever you wish to call the expressers of these digital narratives, allows the viewer to now be a participant.  In natural life we are all participants influencing the world depending on our actions.  No matter how greatly we wish to just be observers our presence alters every moment.  These stories truly demonstrate that natural state and force people to recognize that they are not just observers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the breakdown of time, digital storytelling has opened up a realm where we can begin to question our own interpretation of time within our own physical existence.  It begs to question why our natural thought processes don’t function linearly and yet the stories we tend to tell ourselves do.  Now as we break down the linearity of stories we open up routes to an intimacy that has struggled to be portrayed in past story telling methods.  We can step into someone else’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, with the advent now of VR, the concept of presence is talked about as an important element of the future of storytelling.  If we can make someone feel like they are there in that place, interacting with their environment in the same way they would interact with their physical environment, maybe we can stimulate something within them that was unobtainable before?  As technology continues to advance how will the future of storytelling change and affect humanities perception of the world?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 15:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/11/Storytelling_in_the_Digital_Age.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/11/Storytelling_in_the_Digital_Age.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Irrational vs. Rational</title>
        <description>&lt;body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rationality is viewed as a virtue in our society.  It is a concept that most strive to achieve in their interactions in life.  We often find ourselves, when engaging with decisions, attempting to move towards the more rational choice; however, there are some feelings that are so completely irrational we can’t help but feel them.  Where do these feelings have a place?  Why do these feelings pull us in the directions that they do?&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I have never been one to strictly move within rational space.  I have many times gone for the irrational choice because it just felt right.  Yet I’m older now.  I’ve seen what some of those irrational choices can lead to.  And I don’t regret them.  I never would, but the irrational choice is usually not the easiest choice.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;It’s safer to live in a rational world.  With rationality comes logic and definition and a foreseen conclusion.  But this world isn’t rational.  We don’t live in the scientific model that we have constructed.  We live in a world where things can’t always be predicted.  We create rational models but we live in an irrational world.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;How have we defined what is reasonable?  If being rational is being reasonable then what is reason?  Where did we decide that certain actions or thoughts were reasonable while others were not?  Being rational is being influenced by reason and not emotions??? Why are emotions not reasonable? When did we decide that emotions were unreasonable or rather irrational?  Followed by that being rational is being of sound mind otherwise known as sane.  Is this to say that being influenced by emotion is not a sane way to interact and engage with life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find myself questioning rationality vs irrationality as I attempt to merge not only certain elements of science and art, but also the sides of myself that are more artistic and scientific.  The left and the right brain, as some may say. When integrating subjects there is always the challenge of finding the ways to communicate the connections that to you are so apparent, but there is also the challenge of balancing your own emotional being on two separate planes of existence. &lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;As an artist I find myself becoming lost in the outer reaches of my own reflections and thought.  There are times when I find it hard to return back to Earth.  Time becomes a variant and space dissolves.  I feel deeply emotional and connected to an ether otherwise invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a scientist I have both feet planted firmly on the ground.  Every detail of every task is adamantly apparent.  I observe things as they logically occur and refuse to act on emotion without fully analyzing the outcomes of my choices.  In this space I become a highly functional member of society, but I can’t help feeling there is something I am missing out on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as I devise my story I feel a love triangle between humanity, science, and art will need to be explored.  There is a struggle that exists when you operate on both planes, yet this struggle is what can lead you to the most innovative perceptions of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2016-09-10-rational_4_3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto&quot;&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
 
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/10/DS_Irrational_Rational.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/10/DS_Irrational_Rational.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brainstorms</title>
        <description>&lt;body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a solid brainstorming session, with my good friend Olivia, further working on the story development for my thesis project.  We got into a deep discussion of resonance and I realized that resonance is what I should be focusing on over harmonic motion.  While both are related concepts, resonance builds on harmonic motion as an expression of the relationships and connections between frequencies.  I was reminded of a poem I once wrote: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
I met you and we resonated.  
Our frequencies matched.
Constructive interference 
The amplitude now your wave plus mine.
Do you feel it.
The way the energy soared. 
When we walked into the room. 
Together.
In perfect time.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I question how I can express this concept visually.  If two people staring at eachother from different worlds can see and recognize the connection that they share, how do others percieve this?  I now must reference another statement that I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
There are moments when the wall between our paths becomes transparent and we see 
each other standing there.  We reach out and for one brief second in time we 
connect and for one brief moment I am reminded that I’m not alone.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in life there are people that you meet, that make life seem so much more grounded.  They remind you that it's not you who is the crazy one, but the world that does not know how to find a place for you.  This piece is just as much about &lt;b&gt;connection&lt;/b&gt; as anything else.  I can't forget about humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src= &quot;/media/2016-09-09-DSBstorm1.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src= &quot;/media/2016-09-09-DSBstorm2.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/09/DSBrainstorms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/09/DSBrainstorms.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Immersivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was little I used to wake up to hearing someone playing piano.  I would walk downstairs and nobody would be there.  I have always heard melodies constantly playing in my mind.  I have always seen vivid visual images.  I have always wanted to get them out of mind.  These experiences for me feel very immersive.  If I close my eyes I can see and hear things to the point I feel the experience all over my body.  I have always wanted to share this feeling with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/07/DSImmersive.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/07/DSImmersive.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scenes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Story Overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Scene 1: Montessori School – 

	•	Space is completely open with a variety of interactive installations set up that explore teaching 
	about sound, math, physics, psychology, etc… In an interactive and playful way.  

	•	Our character is playing and encouraging others to play.  

Scene 2: Chairs – 

	•	Desks are brought in to the space as the Montessori scene is broken down.  Audience members 
	are encouraged to sit within the chairs. 

	•	Our character is refusing to sit, trying to avoid being shuffled into a chair. 

Scene 3: Departments – 

	•	Walls are pushed into the space separating the space into four quadrants.  Each quadrant 
	represents a different subject, broken down into physics, psychology, art, and music.  

	•	Our character fights against those that are trying to get them to sit in the desk.  They can’t sit or 
	interact with the space in a normal way.  They are drawing on the walls and being disruptive.  

Scene 4: Corporate America – 

	•	The walls are replaced by people marching in black suits with briefcases.  

	•	Our character is fighting to get through the walls that they have created.  At moments it is a 
	violent fight.  

	•	Finally our character pushes their way to the center they scream and watch as all the walls come 
	tumbling down. 

Scene 5: Building a new world – 

	•	Our character uses elements of physics, psychology, art, and music to bring together concepts of 
	harmonic motion and create a final finale piece. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/05/DSScenes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/05/DSScenes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
