<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monica Bolles</title>
    <description>This is an expression of me.  Here you may find my art, my life, my love.   Most importantly the conversations of an artist in the world of science.   
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 13:51:51 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 13:51:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to live in a digital culture?  As I write this I am sitting in a coffee shop looking at the surrounding people all alone, drinking their coffee, typing away at their computers, just as I am doing.  We are all disconnected from the world around us, lost in whatever this magical screen has to offer.  If I stare at it long enough I almost feel like I would get sucked into the portal of digital space the computer’s open jaw has created… if only this damned glass wasn’t in the way.  And this is our world now.  It wasn’t always this way.  I remember the days where computers were more of a novelty, but now they are everywhere.  They are our companions and our best friends.  I probably spend more time with my computer then any one person in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two people just sat down across from me.  They have grey hair and a carefree appearance.  They look like they’re from Boulder when Boulder wasn’t the yuppie village it has turned into today.  They make a comment on the state of the coffee shop.  They question what socialization will look like in a few years from now.  Are we losing our abilities to socialize?  I find myself socializing with my computer right now.  Microsoft Word and I are having a wonderful conversation.  I feel like I can communicate better with some sort of inanimate technology that allows me to write my thoughts and express my feelings with no judgment.  Right now as I write I know that I can say whatever I want and if I decide I want to share what I have written with other humans I can edit, delete, and control my stream of thought.  The magic of Word is that I can easily do this and no one will ever know what was once written in this space.  The digital world seems safe.  Like you can express your deepest darkest secrets and no one will ever know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now find myself distracted by the fact these people across from me are having a conversation.  The man speaking has a soft spoken voice yet it seems deafening in the midst of computer typing and coffee pouring.  I begin to wonder why they can’t just join the masses in the quiet solemn of laptop central.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, contemplating the relationship I share with my computer, this coffee shop, and the people around me, wondering what it means to live in the world we do today.  I question where the lines blur.  Where it is that forms a distinction between my fingers on the keyboard of my computer and the computer itself.  Am I part of the computer?  Are we separate entities?  Or does the connection of my hands to its soft surface somehow define a connection that unifies me to computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what about the content?  Am I separate from what I read, explore, experience within this space?  The computer offers a chance to look into a portal of a world based on 1s and 0s that somehow form images, words, and interactions.  It doesn’t seem much different than the world out there, except I can manipulate, distort, control, and contain it.  It’s actually very different than the world out there, but again the lines between digital and physical reality seem blurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe we are separate from our digital selves.  I believe they are an extension of us that we’ve manipulated and controlled to be the greatest avatar we could imagine would represent who we are to the world.  And the world sees us.  I have around 900 Facebook friends.  I get to know these friends by their posts.  Most of them I haven’t had a physical conversation with in years.  Some of them I’ve only met once.  But I know them.  I know them by the things they say and the pictures they post.  I know where they’ve been, who they’ve loved, what they do for a living.  I can say “Oh, yeah! So and So is married now and with kids but they just traveled to Europe for some time.  It looks like they’re really enjoying life and having a good time.”  But I haven’t talked to this person in ages.  I don’t even know if they remember who I am.  But I act like I know them.  Although maybe they borrowed the kid.  They found pictures on google of some European landmarks and photoshopped their image in.  Maybe they photoshopped their partner in too.  You really don’t know, but you think you know, and in your mind that is So and So.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to say as I ramble on is that our digital culture has infiltrated our physical reality and sometimes it is hard to find the line where our physical state begins and the digital world ends.  Social media, professional networks, online streaming services, online news channels, all of the worlds that we experience within this digital box, all of these platforms define our reality.  And so I question, in this day and age, in the midst of what one could describe as digital culture, where do we begin and where do we end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2016-11-28-StreamMing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Streaming&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2016-11-28-Netorked.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Networked&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2016-11-28-tV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Media&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2016-11-28-Browser.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Browser&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2016-11-28-Social_Media.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Socail Media&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 06:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/12/04/Media_World.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/12/04/Media_World.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Aesthetic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The New Aesthetic is a term coined by James Bridle on his Tumblr blog that explores the aesthetic that arises through the relationships between the human and physical world and digital culture.  The term and blog blew up when Bridle hosted a panel at SXSW in 2012.  There was something about putting a name to the curated pictures, articles, and websites that stimulated something within the community of bloggers and writers that attended his panel that year.  There was something worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the term New Aesthetic is a new one to me the images and information Bridle posts on his blog are not.  I recognized most immediately as images friends have posted on Facebook, as images I have posted on Facebook, as conversations I have had with different artists as we discuss our interests in the relationships between physical and digital planes, and as art I have seen in galleries or exhibitions.  The artistic implications are concepts I even play with and explore within my own artistic practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Sterling stated in his article An Essay on the New Aesthetic, “The New Aesthetic concerns itself with ‘an eruption of the digital into the physical.’ That eruption was inevitable. It’s been going on for a generation. It should be much better acculturated than it is.”  He also quotes, “ 
Anybody with a spark of perception who looks through this thing: (&lt;a href=&quot;http://new-aesthetic.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;James Bridle’s New Aesthetic Blog&lt;/a&gt;) must recognize that modern reality is on display there.”  Both quotes address the accentuation of the fact that this movement has been happening for a while. It is all around us and in everything thing we do.  Artists are of course flocking to the creation of pieces that comment on the relationships we share with digital technology.  The digital space has become so much a part of our reality that the lines between physical and digital existence barely exist.  What kind of world would we live in if artists of our time didn’t create commentary about this relationship?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I had the privilege to have an elongated conversation about just this topic with Brian Kane.  We were discussing my personal interests in the manipulation of the physical within the digital space.  I had been working with 3D scanning and found it fascinating the ways in which we can take a representation of something so physical, like the human body, and manipulate and distort it so easily within the digital space.  This concept was nothing new to Brian Kane as he was one of the initiators in the art of video remixing.  In the 90’s he would take news footage and find ways to manipulate, distort, and remix it into new and reimagined video montages.  He began to describe his current interests in taking the digital and making it physical.  He was fascinated in taking pixelated images and creating physical body suits that mimicked this look.  Looking on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://briankane.net/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; today I would say he is almost the poster child for the New Aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what I find most interesting about this “movement”, is not necessarily the movement, but the reaction of the commentators.  Maybe it is my ignorance to the art world, but the apparent reaction to Bridle’s coined term, The New Aesthetic, seems hyped and over excited.  While his blog is definitely interesting and hosts a great curation of works questioning the physical/digital relationships of our time, these works existed long before he placed them on a blog.  This kind of art should be more “acculturated” then it is, for it is the kind of art that explores and questions our modern world.  Maybe this is why Bridle’s curation has elicited the response that it has, he took something that was right there in front of our faces and gave it a name and a place.  Either way I do believe that this is the art of our times and this “New Aesthetic” will only continue to develop, evolve, and morph as the changes in technology question our everyday existence.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 13:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/10/30/New_Aesthetic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/10/30/New_Aesthetic.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>360 Revolution</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creative.colorado.edu/~bolles/360revolution/index.html&quot;&gt;360 Revolution: A Curated 360-Degree Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/10/23/360_Revolution.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/10/23/360_Revolution.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a lot the concept of time and the ways in which we perceive time in relationship to storytelling.  I have become recently inspired by hypertext electronic literature and the ways in which it breaks down the normal conception of how we tell stories in a linear fashion.  Hypertext is somewhat the choose your own adventure model; however, in many of the pieces I have been reading it becomes much more personal than that.  In Shelly Jackson’s My Body there is intimacy to the way the story reads.  It’s almost like you are within her mind and her thoughts.  You can travel through her thinking in a way that traditional timelines don’t allow.  How may I tell this story of Resonance seen through different lenses in a way where the timeline is broken apart, rewound, paused, and fast-forwarded? In our digital space we can do things with time that is impossible to do in our physical environment.  How can I use the digital space to manipulate the timelines within my story?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 04:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/10/08/DSTime.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/10/08/DSTime.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lens</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Through this process I am recognizing themes that are arising.  One word that I am feeling particularly keen towards is “Lens”.  In going through this process of looking at a particular subject from the perspectives of different people within certain disciplines, I have found myself using the word “lens” to describe those perspectives.  I am beginning to question how can I visualize and/or sonify this experience of looking at the concept of resonance through different lenses?  What would those lenses look like?  What would they be?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 06:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/10/05/DSLens.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/10/05/DSLens.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tim Gulsrud</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I interviewed Tim Gulsrud who is a practicing acoustician.  This means he consults architectural firms in how to design buildings to best suit the acoustic needs of the client.  During our conversation while talking about using physics to understand how the sound is interacting with the physical space he said, “It gets so complicated so fast.  It shows you the limitations of the physics.  We might say, ‘We’ve got this figured out.  We’ve got this reverberation time equation, we’ve got these axial mode calculations, it’s simple math’… But the part of the spectrum where low frequency modes really happen is up to 100 HZ, I might calculate them up to 150 maybe 200 HZ depending on the size of the room, but beyond that it gets so complicated it’s just not worthwhile.  The math just breaks down.  The engineer might say, well don’t worry, all you have to worry about is up to 200HZ, but as an audio engineer if you said all I have to worry about is up to 200 HZ, that right there shows you the limitations of the math and that’s cutting edge acoustics.  It just becomes impractical.”  I found this statement interesting as it describes the ways in which science and math can really only take us so far in our understanding of the world around us.  At a certain point the tools don’t work and you have to rely on your human experience to make further decisions and analysis.  How can I demonstrate the limitations of science and where we must cross into the realm of art?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another topic we talked in depth about was the exploration of standing waves within a room.  There is an experiment which involves placing a speaker at different locations in the room and exciting room modes.  “Room modes are the collection of resonances that exist in a room when the room is excited by an acoustic source such as a loudspeaker. Most rooms have their fundamental resonances in the 20 Hz to 200 Hz region, each frequency being related to one or more of the room’s dimension’s or a divisor thereof”, says Wikepedia.  You can experience these room modes by walking around the space during a time that a speaker is exciting one of the modes and at different places in the room you will hear a rise in the volume of sound and then a lowering in the volume.  I am wondering what kinds of interesting artistic effects may be explored in the excitation of room modes?  What can we explore in the peaks and null points?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 12:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/10/02/DSTim_Gulsrud.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/10/02/DSTim_Gulsrud.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sara Ludy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sara Ludy had grown up in Virginia where she became inspired by painting the surrounding nature.  Her painting skills eventually gained her a scholarship to SAIC. It was here that she learned about new media art and left painting behind.  Her style and practice took shape as she began to explore the realms between digital and natural spaces.  Much of her work now focuses on the documentation and creation of digital architecture and nature.  One of her notable pieces is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://projectionmonitor.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Projection Monitor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and can be followed on Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This piece is a series of photographs taken in Second Life.  What is fascinating about this piece is the comparison that is being made between physical real estate and digital real estate.  While it is common for people to photograph their physical surroundings and have a desire to document their physical space, it is very rare to see people documenting their digital space.  You don’t go on Facebook and see pictures of people’s interactions on Facebook.  That is not something, at least anyone that I know, posts about.  Yet you see pictures of many other physical life events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sara Ludy has decided to document Second Life, a digital world modeled after our own.  It makes perfect sense to document it, to take pictures and share them, just like you would anything else from your life.  I believe a powerful statement is made in this action.  It almost becomes a declaration for the onset of virtual reality.  It asks the question, are these virtual spaces worth documenting?  And in Sara Ludy’s actions, I believe, she thinks yes.  I don’t think much of our mass recognizes the fact that with the creation of our digital world we have created an alternate reality that has become so familiar we don’t even realize we now live between two worlds.  Second Life is only an example of one of the many virtual experiences that our digital technology provides, and with Sara Ludy’s decision to document its rooms and landscapes she brings this reality more to light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other interesting feature to her exploration of the digital world is that this documentation never includes people.  She is very fascinated with home structures and plants, but there are no people to be seen.  It creates a very ghostly and lonely feel to her photos and videos.  In some of her more recent pieces, she has been fascinated with building her own 3D Models of homes.  She has one piece called &lt;a href=&quot;http://animalnewyork.com/2014/tour-sara-ludys-digital-dream-house/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dream House&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in which she is continually expanding on building a house.  It has many different rooms and is decorated with plant life but there are no animals or people that exist within this space.  She also made a music video for the band … called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8vI5nyWBZmg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;House On Fire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  This video takes you on an exploration of a virtual house again empty and devoid of animals or people.  By not including virtual people within especially a virtual home, a place where you would expect to see people, the stark reality of virtual reality stares you in the face.  Life doesn’t exist here.  Only an emulation of something that is similar to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her &lt;a href=&quot;http://intelligentsiagallery.com/Interview-with-Sara-Ludy&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Intelligentsia Gallery Sara Ludy states, “When I’m not working, I spend time visiting abandoned and haunted places, attempting to access history through clair senses. I’m interested in how information from past events resides in space; where land and architecture becomes a memory bank.”  Her fascination with what could be considered the “aura” of space, and the ways that footprints of those before her decorate the halls with a residue of history and purpose reveals a different interpretation to the lack of people within her documentation.  While abandoned and haunted buildings hold that same feeling of loneliness that empty virtual homes do, they also hold memories of the past.  The question that was brought up earlier by Walter Benjamin about artistic reproductions losing aura is now brought heavily to the surface.  Do virtual spaces have an “aura”?  Do they also contain a memory bank?  A sense that someone was once here, but no longer is?  Are those footsteps of the people that Trod through Second Life still ringing through the digital corners of virtual hallways?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that same interview Sara Ludy explains, “My practice explores the nature of immateriality and space as a medium. Digital tools allow me to give form to the intangible without the form becoming physical. I like that I can represent a presence with digital dust. I find that to be beautiful. I’m interested in the fluidity of spaces such as digital, dream, intuitive, psychological, emotional, psychic and spiritual; how their formal qualities, stories and ghosts move between each other and leave imprints.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this statement it seems clear that Sara Ludy believes that we do leave imprints within digital space.  That presence can be found in “digital dust”.  Our relationship to our digital world has definitely left an imprint on us.  Have we left an imprint on it?  Our entire culture is changing at a rampant pace.  The digital technology that existed twenty years ago is archaic and historical.  It represents a time when the breath of change was on the horizon.  Now change is all we know.  What happens when we lose these virtual spaces?  When Second Life is long forgotten.  Will we look to Sara Ludy’s photos and state, there was once life here, but now this place has been abandoned and forgotten.  All we have now are footsteps left to decorate the digital dust of what once was a thriving place.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 13:19:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/28/Sara_Ludy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/28/Sara_Ludy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Net Art and Curation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the advent of the internet it was to be certain that artists would find ways to interact, build, and create ‘’art” for such a landscape.  As with any development of an idea that would form a paradigm shift into our next level of evolution, there were those that recognized the potential of the net for being a space where current constructs could be deconstructed and the future could be built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The net offers users a unique perspective on interaction.  Users are encouraged to click, play, and examine each page.  They may never have the time or patience to explore every single aspect a website has to offer, yet there is an ever present engagement with the ‘surf-the-web’ experience.  This idea of ‘click-holes’ has become a household term.  Everyone is familiar with the time they have spent down the rabbit’s hole of clicking on links.  Net art has often fully explored this concept.  Hypertext novels and electronic literature riddle pages with links to other pages, with links to even more pages, by the time you look up you’re not even sure where you started or where you have gone.  The journey fails temporal linearity as it capitalizes and perpetuates the attention disordered culture that we live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in this world artists have been given an opportunity to engage with their viewers/(users(?)) in a different way than traditional art galleries may afford.  As a child I remember the stiff atmosphere of an art gallery.  The cold white walls would decorate the paintings that stood still and iconic. Velvet ropes defined the borders between appreciation and criticism.  Guards were the warriors of silence and artistic preservation.  Words were meant to be whispered and hands were meant to stay by one’s side.  Maybe it was just me, but I always wanted to tear through all the borders and constrictions to feel the texture of the paint against my fingers.  I was sure that the artist’s secrets were held in between the strokes of paint that defined its mastery.  But in this environment the art seemed meant for only those that had the privileged knowledge that gave them the right to critically disseminate and dismantle the stagnant imagery hung on the wall by uttering pompous remarks about what they could only theorize was an artistic meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net art on the other hand is for anyone and everyone, but mostly for those who take the time to engage.  Human exploration is key to understanding this art form. There is no velvet rope, there are no guards, this art can be experienced in the privacy of your own home, or when surrounded by people at a coffee shop or library.  You can share, you can never tell a sole, there are many choices to how you experience net art and all of it comes down to the way in which you choose to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curation of net art can be just as interactive and engaging.  The art gallery of the net can be whatever you define.  One of my personal favorites is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.easylife.org/desktop/&quot;&gt;Desktop It&lt;/a&gt;.  The gallery itself is an artistic statement to your desktop.  Within it are links to over fifty different pictures of desktops as well as some net art pieces.  However, this site also brings to light the inherent nature of curation in digital space, site deletion or movement.  Many of the links on this page are broken and thus is the case with many sites of curation.  It’s as if the artist walked into the art gallery and pulled their painting off the wall leaving a gaping hole to be observed by the masses.  Or maybe their piece was stolen, maybe there was a fire, maybe this art now exists nowhere and all we are left with is a blinking white page with a responding error message that makes us wonder if there was anything here to begin with at all.  The impermanence of net art is inherent within the medium.  While there is something so tangible to the way we interact and engage with it, there is also nothing physically viable that will define its existence for any guaranteed amount of time.  This art exists outside of space and will only exist for as long as the artist chooses to water and feed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I am a fan of the breaking down of borders, constitutions, and definitions.  The evolution of art within the net/web space has been at the forefront of challenging concepts of art and government for a while.  It asks questions about community, viewer engagement, scientific understanding, and even strives to redefine our current definitions of art and curatorial space.  My own interests lie heavily within examining the lines that blur art and science. The artist is now a scientific monger exploring at great depths the science and nature of their artistic expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EleVr is a research group that creates a series of art projects to explore and research their topics of interest.  In the project “&lt;a href=&quot;http://elevr.com/portfolio/monkey-see-monkey-do/&quot;&gt;Monkey See, Monkey Do&lt;/a&gt;” they built a 360-degree virtual reality environment in which the viewer can manipulate the number of monkeys they see in four dimensional space.  In their video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=286&amp;amp;v=ubfOeOtCNo4&quot;&gt;4Dmonkey.gif&lt;/a&gt; the evolution of art within these programmatic spaces is explored, and the lines that justify the separation of science and art become blurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thejohnnycashproject.com/&quot;&gt;The Johnny Cash Project&lt;/a&gt; is a massive web collaboration project to remix and recreate a “living portrait” of Johnny Cash. The website allows anyone to download and paint over a frame of Johnny Cash’s music video for “Ain’t No Grave”.  Anyone can then vote on their favorite frames and the ones that gain the most popularity are put into a music video that you can watch.  The frames that are included are changing all the time due to new frames being built and voted into existence.  The website offers up the potential for collaboration from people around the world and is a piece of art within itself.  It begs to question if art these days is ever a finalized piece of work or more of a platform to encourage new ways of human engagement and interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net art has grown and evolved since it’s early days.  Technology has advanced to a level where many things originally thought to be impossible are readily accessible.  We are entering into a new phase where web browsers can process 3D modeling, interactive audio, virtual reality, and large scale interactive projects.  This opens up a new world of creativity to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- *References:* 

[http://www.easylife.org/desktop/][desktop]

[http://elevr.com/portfolio/monkey-see-monkey-do/][monkey]

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=286&amp;v=ubfOeOtCNo4][4Dmonkey]

[http://www.thejohnnycashproject.com/][cash] --&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 12:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/18/Net_Art_and_Curation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/digitalarthistory/2016/09/18/Net_Art_and_Curation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>digitalArtHistory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Objective and Method</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Objective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To contemplate the theory of resonance through the integration of physics, psychology, art, and music in an interactive multimedia performance piece accompanied by an interactive hypertext novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Method:  Hypertext&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the written presentation of my work I will create a hypertext that explores my thought process as well as the meetings and interactions that define the core moments of my research.  The hypertext will host written reflections on interviews, readings, and experiments as well as audio, video clips, and illustrations.  This method is meant to explore the relationships and connections that form between thoughts, conversations, and experiences during the research and creation process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/15/DSObjective_and_Method.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/15/DSObjective_and_Method.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>School</title>
        <description>&lt;body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in elementary school I attended Montessori school.  The classroom was an open room with mostly floor space.  There were no chairs and we would usually sit on the floor.  I can still picture the layout of the space.  There was a corner across from the door that allowed us entrance into the classroom.  In this corner there were stacks of books.  In the book corner existed a list that had many recommended readings on it.  I made it a point to check off as many of these readings from this list as I could.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;If you turned to your right, when in the book corner, there was one larger table with chairs.  We mostly used this space to make art or any project that you were working on that required a table.  Every year we would create a group art project and present it at the Boulder Art Museum.  We would go on a field trip to see it.  One year we created a quilt inspired by the artist Faith Ringgold.  We came up with the concept as a group and then each of us created a square that was later sewn into one larger whole.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;Most of the space; however, was just an open floor.  Here we would sit in a circle and play music, write, study, and learn.  Every morning we would start the day out by journaling in a notebook.  I still have the stacks of black and white etched composition books that we would write in.  It was here I learned about poetry and wrote many of my first poems.  It was also here I learned about astronomy and became fascinated with the stars and the history of all the men and women who had travelled to the moon.  Each subject flowed into the next.  There were no lines or distinctions.  The space was safe, bright, and inviting.  It was in this space I began developing many of my strongest skillsets.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;When I finally began attending public school I found it challenging to sit in the classroom the way they expected us to sit.  The desks were uncomfortable and I found it difficult to listen to the teacher as they droned on about who knows what. I would get in trouble for doodling on my notebook, or doing my homework in class, but I still managed to get straight A’s.  Mostly I was just bored.  It was easy to just remember information and regurgitate it, and writing seemed pretty natural to me at that point.  I don’t have many clear memories about my classes and what I learned during this time. What I do remember were my friends and the social connections I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I reached college I rediscovered my passion for learning.  My classes were harder, I could choose what subjects I wanted to study, and I had a big beautiful open campus to explore.  I still struggled to sit in a desk ‘properly’, but for the most part I was excited and stimulated about the knowledge that was to be gained.  Pretty quickly I learned that the university didn’t have a program that integrated all of the subjects that I was interested in so I devised my own program combining physics, psychology, art, and music.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;I was amazed at how many people would ask me how these subjects connected.  To me it was obvious.  Physics was the study of optics and acoustics, psychology was sensation and perception, and art was the application of these studies.  I think it is the drive to make these connections and the realization that they are not immediately apparent to everyone that makes me have the desire to create the art I wish to create.&lt;/p&gt;  


&lt;/body&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 05:18:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/14/DSSchool.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/designstudio/2016/09/14/DSSchool.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>designStudio</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
